HALID BUSAYR CEYLAN

London, UK | | M: 07470534435 | halid@automateops.co.uk - Contractor

SUMMARY

A skilled CKA: Certified Kubernetes Administrator, RHCE: RedHat Certified Engineer, AWS: Certified SysOps Administrator.

Senior AWS Architect & DevOps consultant with 8+ experience in AWS & 3+ experience Mesosphere and Kubernetes in production.

I have completed several projects and build CI/CD pipelines, containerization projects such as Mesosphere, Kubernetes and applications on the Cloud. Starting from scratch, migrating legacy systems to the Cloud, designing scalable architectures are my area of expertise.

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/hbceylan/

GitHub: https://github.com/hbceylan

EDUCATION

Information Management **Anadolu University Business Administration** Anadolu University

SKILLS

Building applications: Java, Scala, Golang, React

Architecture: Microservices Scripting: Bash, Golang

Infrastructure as Code: Terraform, Ansible, Puppet,

Cloud: AWS, GCP, Azure

Amazon Web Services (AWS): EC2, VPC, ASG, ELB, Route53, RDS, Kinesis, EKS, DynamoDB, ElastiCache, ElasticSearch, SES, SQS, S3, CloudWatch, CloudFront, SystemManager

Containerization: Docker

Continues Integration and Continues Delivery:

Jenkins

Databases: Cassandra, PostgreSQL, DynamoDB,

Redis, MySQL, Solr

Container Orchestration: Kubernetes, DCOS, Mesos Logging: Elasticsearch, Logstash, Kibana

Monitoring: Prometheus-Grafana, Instana, NewRelic Proxying: Nginx, Nginx-Ingress, Traefik, Cloudflare Versioning: Git, Git flow, GitHub, Bitbucket

Agile: Scrum, Sprint

CERTIFICATIONS

CNCF: Certified Kubernetes Administrator AWS: AWS Certified SysOps Engineer RHCE: RedHat Certified Engineer

RHCSA: RedHat Certified System Administrator

RHCT: RedHat Certified Technician MCP: Microsoft Certified Professional

MCSA: Microsoft Certified System Administrator MCSE: Microsoft Certified System Engineer MCTS: Microsoft Certified Technology Specialist

EXPERIENCE

05/2018 to Current

Senior DevOps Engineer

Hazelcast

I have completed 2 valuable and big project as a Senior DevOps Engineer at Hazelcast which provides the leading in-memory computing platform for high-performance data processing at scale, accelerating applications for the most innovative global brands.

Hazelcast Cloud: Hazelcast Cloud is as a service for Hazelcast IMDG. I have built Hazelcast Cloud infrastructure with IaC practices. I used Terraform and Kubernetes in this project. All Kubernetes clusters running on AWS. I have used a lot of AWS services such as EC2, VPC, ASG, ELB, S3, RDS, Route53, SQS, SNS etc. in this project. Also, I have implemented CloudFlare for DDoS and other security protection.

Hazelcast Cloud Dedicated: Hazelcast Dedicated is running on customer dedicated infrastructure. As a team we write some microservices with Golang and I have built Hazelcast Cloud Dedicated infrastructure with IaC practices. I used Terraform and Kubernetes in this project. Kubernetes clusters running on multi cloud such as AWS, GCP and Azure.

Cimri

I had an active role throughout development as a DevOps Engineer at Cimri.com which is a leading price and product comparison company in Turkey. I have built cimri.com infrastructure with Mesosphere stack.

I used Ansible for automation. All infrastructure built with IaC practices and all servers running on AWS. I have used Kubernetes for test environment and a lot of AWS services such as EC2, VPC, ASG, ELB, S3, RDS, KINESIS, DYNAMODB etc. in this project. Also, I have implemented CloudFlare for DDoS and other security protection.

05/2015 to 06/2016 Senior Linux System Administrator

Unnado

Unnado is an e-commerce company that sells especially baby supplies. When I start unnado.com as a Senior Linux Administrator, all company servers running on a local datacenter with legacy operating system. So, we had a lot of scalability issues in peak times. I have migrated all servers from local datacenter to AWS with no downtime.

I used a lot of AWS service such as EC2, VPC, ASG, ELB, S3, RDS, ELASTICACHE etc. in this project. Also, I have implemented CloudFlare for DDoS and other security protection.

04/2014 to 05/2015 Linux System Administrator

EmlakJet

EmlakJet is Turkey's largest property portal. I have managed more than 50 linux servers in data center and implemented monitoring system, authentication mechanism and so on. My responsibilities was about management, maintenance and troubleshooting web applications, virtualization systems and network operations.

03/2013 to 04/2014 Co-Founder and Linux System Administrator

SınavaDoğru

Along with being Co-Founder at Sınava Doğru, where we provide a unique online test experience for students who study for Open University in Turkey, I have designed and implemented infrastructure from scratch using AWS cloud environment. I used some AWS services such as EC2, VPC, ASG, ELB, S3, RDS, Route53. Management, maintenance and troubleshooting web applications, virtualization systems and network operations.

iLab

I have managed approximately 7 company's infrastructure in this organization with my team. We have migrated 3 company's infrastructure from local data center to AWS. Planning of IT infrastructure and needs of companies within iLab Holding.

02/2010 to 02/2011 System Administrator

iLab

Management, maintenance and troubleshooting web applications, Linux and Windows servers, virtualization systems and network operations.

03/2008 to 02/2010 System Engineer

Treda

Management, maintenance and troubleshooting Windows servers, network devices and, bare metal servers.

03/2004 to 01/2008 System Technician

CE Computer

Management

Maintenance and troubleshooting client computers.